biolegend.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy

Everyone at BioLegend, Inc. (collectively, “BioLegend,” “we” and “us”) know you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about how we collect, store, use and disclose information about you when you interact or use our websites (collectively the “Websites”) or any related events, trade shows, sales or marketing, and/or if you use any of our products, including mobile applications (collectively the “Services”) in any manner.

* * *

## **What does this Privacy Policy cover?**

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of information that we gather when you are accessing or using our Websites or Services or when you contact us in any manner. We gather various types of information, including information that identifies you as an individual (“Personal Information”) from our users, as explained in more detail below.

## **What information does BioLegend Collect?**

**Information You Provide to Us:**

_When you use the Websites:_  We may collect any Personal Information that you choose to send to us or provide to us, if you contact us through the Websites, we will keep a record of our correspondence.

_When you use the Services:_  We receive and store information you provide directly to us. For example, when setting up new users, we collect Personal Information, such as name and e-mail address, to provide them with Services. The types of information we may collect directly from our customers and their users include: names, usernames, email addresses, postal addresses, phone numbers, job titles, transactional information (including Services purchased), as well as any other contact or other information they choose to provide us or upload to our systems in connection with the Services.

**Information We Automatically Collect:**

_When you use the Websites:_  When you visit the Website, we collect certain information related to your device, such as your device’s IP address, referring website, what pages your device visited, and the time that your device visited our Website.

_When you use the Services:_  Usage information – we keep track of user activity in relation to the types of Services our customers and their users use, the configuration of their computers, and performance metrics related to their use of the Services.  Log information – we log information about our customers and their users when you use one of the Services including Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. Information collected by cookies and other similar technologies – we use various technologies to collect information which may include saving cookies to users’ computers.

For further information, please see the section below headed “Cookies and other Tracking Technologies”.

**How do we use the information?**

_Websites:_ We will use the information we collect via our Websites (depending upon what cookies you enabled, or forms that you may have filled out) as follows:

  * To administer our Website, our events and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, statistical and survey purposes;
  * To improve our Website to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * Analyze customers’ use of the Websites for trend monitoring, marketing and advertising purposes;
  * For purposes made clear to you at the time you submit your information – for example, to fulfill your request for a demo, to provide you with access to one of our webinar’s or whitepaper’s or to provide you with information you have requested about our Services; and
  * As part of our efforts to keep our Website safe and secure (Automatic).

_Services:_  We may use the information we collect from our customers and their users in connection with the Services we provide for a range of reasons, including to:

  * To set up a user account,
  * Provide, operate and maintain the Services;
  * Process and complete transactions, and send related information, including transaction confirmations and invoices;
  * Manage our customers’ use of the Services, respond to enquiries and comments and provide customer service and support;
  * Send customers technical alerts, updates, security notifications, and administrative communications;
  * Investigate and prevent fraudulent activities, unauthorized access to the Services, and other illegal activities; and
  * For any other purposes about which we notify customers and users.

We may also use the information you send to us via the Websites and/or Services, to communicate with you via email and, possibly, other means, regarding products, services, offers, promotions and events we think may be of interest to you or to send you our newsletter, if this is in accordance with your marketing preferences. However, you will always be able to opt-out of such communications at any time (see the “Your Choices” section below).

**How do we share and disclose information to third parties?**

We do not rent or sell your Personal Information to anyone. We may share and disclose information (including Personal Information) about our customers in the following limited circumstances:  
_Vendors, consultants and other service providers:_   We may share your information with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who we employ to perform tasks on our behalf. These companies include (for example) our payment processing providers, website analytics companies (e.g., [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)), CRM service providers and tech product support (e.g., Salesforce), email service providers (e.g., Sendgrid, GreenRope) and others.

_Business Transfers:_  We may choose to buy or sell assets, and may share and/or transfer customer information in connection with the evaluation of and entry into such transactions. Also, if we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party.

_BioLegend Group Companies:_  We may also share your personal data with our current and future parent companies, subsidiaries and/or affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy.

_Protection of BioLegend and Others:  _We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information as necessary to comply with law or court order; enforce or apply our agreements with you and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of BioLegend, our employees, our users, or others.

_Disclosures for National Security or Law Enforcement:_  Under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your Personal Information in response to valid requests by public authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements.

**Is Personal Information about me secure?**

We use appropriate technical, organizational and administrative security measures to protect any information we hold in our records from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.  Unfortunately, no company or service can guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. Among other practices, your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

**Cookies and other tracking technologies**

Our Websites and some of our Services use cookies (small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters that we put on your computer) and other similar tracking technologies (like web beacons, tags and scripts) to uniquely identify your browser and to gather information about how you interact with the Websites and Services. We use this information for the following purposes:

  * Assisting you in navigation;
  * Assisting in registration, login, and your ability to provide feedback;
  * Analyzing your use of our products, services or applications; and
  * Assisting with our promotional and marketing efforts (including behavioral advertising).

Please consult our [Cookie Declaration](https://www.biolegend.com/en-us/cookie-preferences) for more information about the type of cookies and tracking technologies that we use on this Website and why, and how to accept and reject them.

In HTML-based email announcements, we track and report on recipients that open the email and click on any links. This information is used to enable more accurate reporting on end-user interests, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make our Services and Websites better for our users.

We also utilize Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google, to better understand your use of our Websites and Services. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit the Websites, what pages they visit and what other sites they used prior to visiting. Google uses the data collected to track and examine the use of the Websites, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the data collected on the Websites to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Websites is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Google offers an opt-out mechanism for the web available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

**What choices do I have?**

You can always opt not to disclose information to us, but keep in mind some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features.

**Cookies**

You can accept or reject cookies by clicking “Show details” on the cookie consent banner, or you can update your preferences by clicking the “Change Your consent” button in our [Cookie Declaration](https://www.biolegend.com/cookie_preferences). You can also do so by adjusting your web browser controls. Please consult our Cookie Preferences page for more information about our use of cookies and how to accept and reject them.

**Marketing Communications**

You can opt-out of receiving certain promotional or marketing communications from us at any time, by using the unsubscribe link in the emails communications we send, or by completing the opt-out form available [here](https://www.biolegend.com/en-us/privacy-request-form).

If you have any account for our Services, we will still send you non-promotional communications, like service related emails.

**California residents**  are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please fill out the request form available [here](https://www.biolegend.com/en-us/privacy-request-form).

**Your European Subject Personal Data Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to your personal data where they apply to the particular processing of your personal information:

  * The right to request a copy of your personal data which BioLegend holds about you;
  * The right to request that BioLegend correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
  * The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for BioLegend to retain such data;
  * The right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data at any time;
  * The right to request that BioLegend provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller where applicable;
  * The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing; and
  * The right to lodge a complaint with a European Union Data Protection or Supervisory Authority.

**How can I update and access my information (Exercise my European Subject Data Subject Rights)?**

If you would like to access, review, update, rectify, and delete any Personal Information we hold about you, or exercise any other data subject right available to you under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you can fill out the request form available [here](https://www.biolegend.com/en-us/privacy-request-form). 

Our Privacy team will examine your request and respond to you as quickly as possible, and within 30 days!

Please note that we may still use any aggregated and de-identified Personal Information that does not identify any individual, and may also retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**EU Contact Information**

Data Protection Officer  
8999 BioLegend Way  
San Diego, CA 92121  
Telephone: 858-455-9588

Data Protection Representative  
4B Highgate Business Centre,  
33 Greenwood Place,  
London, NW5 1LB, UK  
Tel: +44 (0)20 3475 3880

**EU Complaints to Supervisory Authorities**

We invite you to let us know about any and all issues either directly by writing to BioLegend’s Data Protection Officer at [Privacy@BioLegend.com](mailto:privacy@BioLegend.com). We will respond through our Data Privacy Officer in writing within 30 days.

If you consider that our processing of your personal data infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work, or the place of the alleged infringement. For example, in the United Kingdom this is the Information Commissioner’s Office, and in Ireland this is the Data Protection Commissioner.

**International Data Transfers**

Personal Information you submit on the Websites or through the Services is sent to the United States and will be primarily processed by us in the United States and potentially in other countries, on our servers or on our hosted service providers’ cloud servers on our behalf. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to those in your country of residence. However, we will always protect your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy wherever it is processed.

**California and Delaware “Do Not Track” Disclosures**

California and Delaware law require BioLegend to indicate whether it honors “Do Not Track” settings in your browser concerning targeted advertising. “Do Not Track” is a standard that is currently under development. As it is not yet finalized, BioLegend adheres to the standards set out in this Privacy Policy and does not monitor or respond to Do Not Track browser requests.

**Linked Websites**

For your convenience, hyperlinks may be posted on the Websites that link to other websites (the “Linked Sites”). We are not responsible for, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to, the privacy practices of any Linked Sites or of any companies that we do not own or control. Linked Sites may collect information in addition to that which we collect on the Websites. We do not endorse any of these Linked Sites, the services or products described or offered on such Linked Sites, or any of the content contained on the Linked Sites. We encourage you to seek out and read the privacy policy of each Linked Site that you visit to understand how the information that is collected about you is used and protected.

**Children**

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any Personal Information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us Personal Information, please fill out the request form available [here](https://www.biolegend.com/en-us/privacy-request-form).

**Will BioLegend ever change this Privacy Policy?**

We’re constantly trying to improve our Websites and Services, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time as well. We will alert you to material changes by, for example, placing a notice on our Websites and/or by sending you an email (if you have registered your e-mail details with us) when we are required to do so by applicable law. You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the date at the bottom of this page. You are responsible for periodically reviewing this Privacy Policy.

**What if I have questions about this policy?**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policies, please fill out the request form available [here](https://www.biolegend.com/en-us/privacy-request-form), and we will try to resolve your concerns.

v3 05/29/2018
